Previously on "Transformers Prime"...
在上一集中
Well, aren't you the clever one?
有一套啊 你这小滑头！
You shall serve as a constant reminder to those who dare
你正好给那些胆敢让我失望之人
fail me.
做个警示！
What?!
什么？！
Three keys are accounted for.
现在有三枚钥匙了
It would seem I have the run of the place.
看来这地儿现在由我做主
Ah, there you are.
啊 在这儿呐！
The fate of Cybertron now rests in Starscream's hands...
无论红蜘蛛有何企图
whatever his intention.
塞博特恩的命运都掌握在他手中了…
Please pardon my unannounced visit, Lord Megatron.
请原谅我的不请自来 威震天陛下
But I have come bearing a peace offering.
小人有礼物敬呈于您…
Few things of value come without a price. So, tell me, Starscream.
天下没有白吃的午餐 说吧 红蜘蛛
What is it that you wish in return?
你想要什么回报？
Only to be a Decepticon once again.
小人只愿重回霸天虎之列
Dreadwing is my first lieutenant now.
我现在的副官是骇翼
And I accept that much has changed during my absence.
在我缺席期间发生的变故 我已坦然接受
I only wish to serve you,
我只想为您效力
my one true master,
我唯一真正的主人
in any way that you deem fit.
任您差遣 绝无怨言
I am deeply impressed by your accomplishment, Starscream.
你此次立下大功 我深感欣慰 红蜘蛛
And know that I will put your offerings to good use,
你的贡献 我必将善加用之
whatever the outcome.
无论结果如何…
Uh, outcome? Of what?
啊 结果？什么结果？！
See to it that Knockout is extracted from the wall.
赶快把击倒从墙中挖出来！
Ah.
啊…
It's good to be back.
人家自由了！
Now, what will we be fishing for today, my liege?
这次您想知道什么呢 我的君王？
Starscream's true motives.
红蜘蛛的真实意图！
Decepticons, it is with deep sorrow
霸天虎们 我怀着沉痛的心情
that I note for the log,
向大家宣告…
Megatron's spark has been extinguished.
威震天的火种已经熄灭了
All hail Starscream.
红蜘蛛…万…岁！
All hail Starscream!
红蜘蛛万岁！
Well, well. You certainly didn't waste any time.
哎呀呀 你可真是惜时如金呐
What?!
什么？！
I just watched you perish!
我刚才看见你已经死了！
I did not perish then,
昔日的我未曾覆灭
and I'm very much with you now...
而今的我与你相随！
the present you
此时此刻你我同在…
as well as the past.
恰如彼时彼刻！
All hail Starscream!
红蜘蛛万岁！
I can't hear you!
本座听不见…
One more time!
再来一次！
All hail Starscream!
红蜘蛛万岁！
This is going to be juicy.
沙发看戏…
Ah! You're inside my head, aren't you?
呃…您正在小人脑中 是么？
The cortical psychic patch.
这是大脑神经接入器
You see, there are no secrets in here... only your memories.
如你所见 此地只有记忆 没有秘密
You cannot manipulate their content
你既无法操纵其内容
or modify their outcome.
也无法修饰其结果
What we see is how it happened.
你我所见的是曾经发生的事实！
If you want to be a true leader, Starscream,
如果你想成为一个真正的首领 红蜘蛛
then stray from Megatron's path
那就不要走威震天的老路
and lead the Decepticons toward peace.
你要带领霸天虎走向和平
I would be willing to consider a truce...
我会真心考虑停战的
if you would be willing to bow before me, Optimus Prime.
只要你真心向我称臣 擎天柱
You have defied my orders yet again!
你又违背本座的命令了！
My mistake, Commander Starscream.
这是我的失误 长官
It is Lord!
叫我陛下！
Haven't you heard?
你没听说吗？
I lead the Decepticons now.
本座如今贵为霸天虎统领！
Now, where did we leave off?
我们看到哪儿了？
Oh, yes.
喔对
"All hail Starscream"?
红蜘蛛万岁？
A rather obvious motif, Starscream.
提一个明显的小小争议：
You deem yourself more able to lead the Decepticons than myself?!
你竟自视比我更有资格领导霸天虎？
No, not anymore.
不！不再是了！
I have learned from my many failures, master.
在经历如此之多的失败以后 主人
Esteemed members of my armada...
我亲爱的成员们
you now stand upon the very precipice of glory... to meet the destiny which I have so tenaciously worked toward.
你们即将见证 本座长久以来不懈追求的光荣时刻
Dynamic leadership of the Decepticons.
霸天虎的领导权应该轮流坐庄！
That clone said it, not me!
那是克隆体说的 不是我！
It seems you would stop at nothing to disrupt my rule,
看来 你并未阻止任何颠覆我政权的言行
including assassination.
包括那场行刺！
It was their idea, not mine!
那是他们的主意 不是我的！
With this creature under your control and at our disposal,
我们有了这种听从你指挥的生物
we might employ it to terminate Megatron,
我们可以用他去了结威震天
allowing us to rule the Decepticons.
夺取霸天虎的控制权
I see no clones here. Was this their idea, too?
这里没有什么克隆体 这也是他们的主意？
I don't remember any of this.
小人对此毫无印象…
I must have been half-crazed at the time,
我那时一定是在抽风呢
a victim of Energon deficiency.
肯定是没能量吃 饿昏了头！
Tell me why I should welcome back someone
告诉我为什么要欢迎你？
whose every waking impulse has been to thwart me,
你生命中的每一次脉冲 都用来刺伤我
undercut me,
暗算我
overthrow me?!
推翻我！
Not true.
绝非如此！
I have always put your well-being before my own.
小人一直视陛下之命重于泰山！
How does this revolting chapter constitute attending to my well-being?
这就是所谓的“重于泰山”？
I was simply trying to help
我只是想帮您
by ridding you of the dark matter polluting your body.
以免黑暗能量污染您的圣体！
Seems I possess the only thing that
看来我拥有唯一一个
would allow you to rise off that slab and walk again,
能让你从病榻上重新站起来的东西！
my dearest Megatron.
最最亲爱的威震天…
I even risked being buried alive for you.
我甚至为您险些被活埋！
I did not abandon you, master.
我…我没有抛下您 主人
I returned to save you!
我回来…是要救您！
Look into my spark, Lord Megatron.
火种可鉴 威震天陛下
My intentions were true.
我是真心的！
Were they, Starscream?
真是如此吗 红蜘蛛？
Were they ever?!
你这辈子真心过吗？
Well, now who has hit rock bottom?
现在轮到谁翻不了身啦？
What's that? I'm sorry.
说什么？对不起
I can't hear you beneath all that rubble.
隔着一座五行山 我什么都听不清
Ha ha... Farewell, Lord Megatron.
哈哈…告辞了 威震天陛下！
May you rust in peace!
愿你一锈到底！
But you have survived far worse.
不过 这种遭遇对你来说是小儿科
If you managed to free yourself,
如果你自己逃了出来
you would blame me for your setback.
就会怪罪我见死不救
And there is nowhere that I could possible escape from your wrath.
你发火的时候 我肯定会理亏
Or, worse yet,
更不用说
your mindless followers will come looking for you
那些傻瓜随从肯定会来找你
and take credit for your rescue...
并因为营救你而立功
credit that could rightfully be mine!
这个功劳 应该属于我！
Ah! Megatron!
啊啊！威震天！
A word of advice?
听我一句忠告…
Stop thinking aloud.
…别再把心里话大声喊出来了！
I don't want to play this game anymore.
我已经不想再玩这个游戏了！
Take the keys.
拿走钥匙吧！
We'll pretend I was never here.
就当这事儿没发生过！
No, Starscream.
没门儿 红蜘蛛！
There are only two possible outcomes
此事只能有两种结果
based upon what I find here in your twisted, little mind.
待我彻底看透你这颗扭曲的心灵之后
If I do not deem that you are worthy of rejoining the Decepticons,
若是我发现你没有资格重回霸天虎之列
you will perish on this very day.
那今天就是你的末日！
Ah. Isn't termination rather extreme?
啊 杀死我是不是过于极端了？
I mean, a really good trouncing usually straightens me out, doesn't it?
我是指…您平日的教训就很有效了…不是么？
No, master. Nooo!
不 主人 不要！
Why wouldn't you wish to harness my talents for the Decepticon cause?
您何不对我作为霸天虎的天赋善加利用呢？
You and I have so much deviousness to offer.
您知道我的狡猾也能派上用场！
Consider it a "welcome home" present.
就当是为您的回归献上的贺礼！
See how generous I can be, my liege?
您瞧 我也可以变得慷慨 陛下！
When it suits you...
你只在必要的时候
Master, that's your plan?!
主人 那就是你的计划？
Bring Autobots back from the dead to attack us?!
复活死掉的汽车人 让我们挨揍？
At other times, you could be quite insulant.
随后 你立即就变得傲慢无礼！
Apologies.
我很抱歉
It's just that I'd gone to so much trouble to terminate the Autobot in the first place.
我只是…初次杀死那个汽车人时 费了不少周折！
Trouble would have been facing him as a gladiator.
只有像战士一样杀死他才会如此！
I've always considered my wits to be my sharpest weapon.
小人一向认为智慧才是最犀利的武器
Wait.
慢着
You two are up to something.
你们想算计我！
You never learn, Starscream.
你从不吸取教训 红蜘蛛
Your arrogance will trump your wits every time.
你的傲慢凌驾于智慧之上！
You cannot harm me
你伤不了我
while Dark Energon flows through my veins! I am invincible!
黑暗能量已经流遍了我的经脉 我已不可战胜！
You're a big one.
你个头很大
This could take a while.
吸收时间要长一点了
What? She's taking credit for scraping him now, too?
什么？她把杀掉他的功劳安在自己头上？！
That was my doing!
那是我干的！
Oh, no! No! Eh... No!
噢不！不要！呃…别开枪！
Any last words, Smokescreen?
有什么遗言吗 烟幕？
My T-Cog.
我的变形齿轮
A, uh... a temporary setback.
嗯 只是一个暂时的小插曲
Other Autobots, other T-Cogs.
还有其他汽车人 其他的变形齿轮
We shall find a replacement soon enough.
我们很快就能找到另一个
Not "soon enough". Now.
那不够快 现在就要！
Huh? Ah! What?
呃…啊！怎么？！
Autobots!
汽车人！
My T-Cog!
我的变形齿轮！
You no longer possess the ability to take flight?!
你已经不能再飞了？
Uh, yes, I-I was going to bring that up.
是的…我刚想说这件事…
And, as you might imagine, my predicament pains me to no end.
您可以想象 我目前的窘境令我无比痛苦！
Fortunately, the Harbingers' tracking systems have remained synched with Megatron's warship.
很幸运 先驱号的追踪系统 还能追踪到威震天的战舰
Of course, we shall require a means of reaching the...
当然我们要先想个办法登上去
Huh? You can transform?!
啊？你们能变形？
Uh, of course you can.
啊对 你们当然能变形！
How else would you fly to the ship?
否则怎么飞到飞船上去？
That was a test in which you all... passed.
我只是想考验一下 你们都通过了
I hope that you might see fit to express your gratitude for the Omega keys
我希望您考虑下帮我重拾飞机形态
by restoring my jet mode.
当做我送来“终极之钥”的回报
After all,
毕竟
would I not be more valuable to you with wings?
能飞的我 对您的用处更大
Ooh, I do transform with an exceptional sense of style.
喔 我每次变形都帅得掉渣！
I said that aloud, didn't I?
呃…我把这句话说出口了 是吗？
Megatron tried to extinguish my spark in cold blood,
威震天不念旧情 想把我干掉
then all but replaced me with that traitorous wretch, Airachnid.
还有那个一心想取代我的混蛋毒蜘蛛
She abandoned me,
她竟然丢下我不管！
left me for scrap!
让我自生自灭！
So why not rat them out?
所以 干嘛不过河拆桥呢？
No one asked you to leave the Decepticon fold.
没人想把你赶出霸天虎阵营
But I wasn't exactly made to feel welcome at the time.
可我当时并不招人待见！
Master, please,
主人 求您了！
give me one more chance! I beg of you!
再给我一次机会吧 我给您磕头了！
Despite the fact that I had seen the error of my ways and dedicated my spark to you.
对于我痛悔往昔并愿意为您 奉献一切的心情 您无动于衷
I have gained a clear understanding of my place in this universe...
我已经认清了自己在宇宙中的位置
of who I am... of who I was always meant to be.
认清了自我 那个自始至终的我
Starscream, second in command,
红蜘蛛 副指挥官
humble servant to Lord Megatron.
威震天陛下的心腹侍从
Until the next opportunity arises to subvert me.
直到你又有机会推翻我！
And how is the patient doing today?
病人今天状况如何？
Same old.
老样子
An inglorious fate that he should remain in this vegetative state.
保持这种植物人状态 真是让他无地自容
On the contrary. Megatron's body may be scrap metal,
正相反 威震天的身体也许成了废铁
but his mind is still percolating.
但他的思维还是很活跃的
Keep that to yourself.
你自己知道就行了！
That blasted Soundwave sees and hears everything.
那该死的声波好像有千里眼和顺风耳！
The eyes and ears of the Decepticons.
他是霸天虎的耳目嘛
Well, as long as their master remains in limbo, so does their cause.
只要他们的主子一天不醒 他们就是群无头苍蝇
The Decepticons deserve a strong, alert leader.
霸天虎急需一位强悍的 警醒的领袖
One who would require a loyal second in command.
这位领袖也需要一个忠诚的副官
A candidate would need to earn that post by making a strong case to said eyes and ears.
要想坐上副官的位置 必须干得漂亮点 才能让那个“耳目”闭嘴
A case for showing mercy, Lord Starscream?
需要发发慈悲吗 红蜘蛛陛下？
Uh-oh.
啊哦
Does this thing have a fast-forward button,
这机器有快进快退按钮吗？
or better yet, erase?
或是删除也行啊！
Knockout, if you would be so kind as to provide your expert medical opinion to Soundwave
击倒 麻烦你向声波讲一下 专家的治疗意见
for the historical record.
以便记录在案
Simply put, unaid, Megatron could remain in this deathless slumber forever.
简单来说 如果没有外力协助 威震天会永远保持这种假死状态
Our master would not have wanted to be seen this way,
我们的主人不会希望自己成为这个样子
to stand idly by while he remains captive in his own body... is not just.
眼看着他的灵魂被禁锢 我们却无所事事 这不公平
Brain-Wave activity... not evidence of consciousness,
脑电波的活动不能证明他拥有意识
but merely of an endless dream from which Megatron may never wake.
只是陷入了无穷的梦境 威震天或许永远都无法醒过来
Soundwave, we must face reality.
声波 我们必须面对现实
Megatron is lost to us.
我们已经痛失威震天
The only honorable option would be to show him mercy.
唯一体面的选择 就是让他解脱
A simple throw of the switch.
只是拨动一个开关而已
When Megatron comes out of it,
等威震天醒来以后
he'll do more than just stick me back in that wall.
就不是把我塞回墙壁里那么简单了！
He'll have Starscream's head and mine!
他会把红蜘蛛的脑袋砍下来 还有我的！
But... if I disconnect before a proper power-down,
不过…如果我在机器关闭之前 就强行拔出接头的话
the link is severed and...
连接就会中断
the big guy will never emerge from Starscream's head.
老大将永远无法从红蜘蛛的脑中逃脱
Everything okay here?
这儿…没问题吧？
Just checking cable integrity.
就是看看接头插好没！
Is it any wonder that I've come to value loyalty above all else?
还有别的事情能拿来评估你的忠诚度吗？
Well, you know,
这个…您知道
we are Decepticons.
咱们可是霸天虎…
I'm sure that even your beloved Dreadwing isn't perfect.
我相信即便是您亲爱的骇翼也并非完美
No one is perfect, Starscream,
人无完人 红蜘蛛
but like his departed twin,
但如同其分离的孪生兄长一般
Dreadwing understands honor.
骇翼他懂得荣耀！
Awaken, warrior.
苏醒吧 战士
Rise and serve your new master!
醒过来 侍奉你的新主人！
Skyquake serves only one master.
天震只侍奉一个主人
Excellent.
很好
Your loyalty and devotion will set a fine example for the troops.
你的忠诚和奉献精神将成为军队的好榜样
No need to be timid, Skyquake.
不必拘谨 天震
You may bow.
俯首称臣吧
You fail to grasp my meaning.
你没听懂我的话
I am here on a mission
派我来这里执行任务的
assigned to me by my one master... Megatron.
是我唯一的主人 威震天
Yes... him.
对 他嘛…
Sadly, Megatron is... no longer with us.
很不幸 威震天已经离我们而去了
Impossible.
不可能！
Why is this so difficult for everyone to accept?
为什么所有人都难以接受事实？
Ah, the grave site of the mighty Skyquake.
啊 强大的天震葬身于此
So quick to reject my authority while you lived.
生前你不假思索地拒绝我的领导
But, as the first of my reanimated warriors,
但作为被我复活的第一名战士
you shall bow to my command.
你应该听我号令！
Ah! Yes! Power of Dark Energon, be mine!
是的…黑暗能量之力…是我的了！
Symbiosis. Hahaha... I can feel it!
融为一体 哈哈哈…我感觉到了！
I understand he perished that day.
他先前不是死去了么？
Well, Skyquake is neither living nor dead
嗯…他既非生者亦非亡者
and no doubt continues to wander through some dimensional neverealm
现在一定仍在另一重维度空间中游荡着
in search of his missing limb.
寻找他的断肢
It would be wise to keep that to yourself around the warship.
你够聪明的话 就别将此事告诉船上的任何人
Awkward.
完了…
B-But, does this mean...
但…您的意思是…？
Yes. I will allow you to return to our ranks
是的 我允许你重回我们的队伍
if only because you are more valuable beside me than against me.
只因这样比与你为敌更为有利！
Oh! Thank the Allspark!
我的个娘啊…感谢火种源！
Infighting has nearly destroyed the Decepticons during your absence.
在你缺席期间霸天虎已经因为内讧而四分五裂了
We must operate as a united front if we are to revive and conquer Cybertron.
如果我们还想征服塞博特恩就必须团结一致
That means each and every one of us, Knockout.
所以谁都不可有二心 击倒！
Megatron sure knows how to patch things up.
威震天可真是会笼络人心啊…
Eh, Dreadwing?
对吧…骇…
Dreadwing?
骇翼？